Sales Enquiry/Helpline

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





MOHAMMAD OMAR SAYED (Featured)



IT Manager seeking roles in Project Management, Information Security, Risk Assessment, Server Administration, System Security, Network Administration, Technical Infrastructure, Technical Support, Vulnerability Management, IT Operations, IT Asset Management



Current Designation: IT MANAGER

Total Experience: 13 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Glenbeigh Records Management

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Current Location: Dubai

Pref. Location: United Arab Emirates (UAE), United Kingdom

(UK).United States (US)

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming

Maintenance

Role: IT/Networking-Mgr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: IT Manager, Networking Manager, Project Management, Information Security, Risk Assessment, Server Administration, System Security, Network Administration, Technical Infrastructure, Technical Support, Vulnerability

Management.IT Operations.IT Asset Management

Verified : Phone Number

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

IT Manager with 10+ years' experience in defining/delivering IT strategies across UAE to meet customer, business & company requirements. Track record within records management, furniture, FMCG and technology industries in Windows Servers Virtualization, Microsoft ERP Systems, Business Continuity Plans, DR Site, as well as ISO27001 Compliance and

Rich understanding of infrastructure along with technologies including multiple platforms, systems, networks, software, hardware, servers, databases, storage, backup and business continuity, etc. Strong ability of managing multiple large scale technology projects, network and system infrastructures, as well as building/leading top performing teams to fuel competitive

Work Experience

Glenbeigh Records Management as IT MANAGER

Mar 2016 to Till Date

KEYACHIEVEMENTS

One of the key employees that contributed to the achievement of ISO 27001-2013 standards in 2016, acquired the certificate, and ensured compliance with the standards

Created Disaster Recovery (DR) site and live replication for critical servers; achieved the RTO and RPO requested by the management; tested it annually and recorded/documented all procedures.

Received appreciation letters from the management 3 times.

Updated company policies and information security procedures, focusing on coordinating information security with suppliers to achieve ISO 27001 standard and high level customer requirements and bank sectors

Conceptualized, designed and created security devices and software to assure the safety of client's information and products

Created in-house IT asset management systemand defined the requirements in close liaison with the development team.

Deployed Password Management System with multifactor authentication.

Passed many audits by information security team of multiple high-level government clients and banks who reviews the organization control and policies in place.

Tested and implemented CIS "Center of internet security" CIS benchmark on all company servers.

Updated IT Infrastructure and segmented the network, deployed Mcrosoft Intune Mobile Device Management and Mobile Application Management for Office 365.

Job Responsibilities

Developing the IT vision, strategy, roadmap and leading the effective execution of the initiatives in alliance with the relevant stakeholders

Managing, developing, training, motivating and retaining a highly skilled team of IT professionals.

Leading, directing and supporting IT strategies, right technologies and creative IT solutions to business problems/requirements

Designing, establishing and enforcing IT systems, processes, policies and procedures as part of company's' ISO

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

2/001 certification.

Maintaining oversight of all IT projects (from Ato Z), ensuring that commitments are properly planned, staffed, monitored and reported

Managing outsourced vendors for all IT related projects and coordinating closely to address/implement all requirements based on the project plan and target date.

Aligning IT projects and strategies with the business objectives and creating the overall IT directions, planning, KPI, budgeting, operations and controls as per the company's mission, vision and objectives.

Communicating effectively (both verbal and writing) with business executives, IT executives, IT personnel and user communities.

Conducting security updates by performing and coordinating regular inspections of systems and network processes.

Planning, controlling and evaluating all IT and electronic data operations; customizing the access to information according to the company rules and necessity.

Assuring the security of backup systems, data and network access by creating live replication plan for all critical services using Veeam backup and replication.

Implementing workable and strategic solutions after identifying problematic areas; reporting to the Business office manager with meaningful commentary.

Working in close liaison with the Sales and Operation department to respond promptly to all customer requirements.

Fairpoint Furniture LLC as IT ADMINISTRATOR

Feb 2014 to Feb 2016

KEYACHIEVEMENTS

Managed and actively involved in many store openings including the set up and configuration of all system and technical requirements.

Implemented ERP System "Mcrosoft dynamics AX 2012 FP & R3" and Al Futtaim technologies - a partner of Mcrosoft in Mddle east and one of the leading Systems Integrator in Mddle East and Lower Gulf.

Opened new Branch at Sheikh Zayed Road for fixing all Computer equipment, POs machines, CCTV, and install Back Store Server, Cabinet, UPS, Telephones and Fingerprint.

Installed active directory, and created user domain policies, folder redirection and backup copy to keep the data safe and clean.

Installed and Fixed Pabx Acatel Lucent Telephone System in coordination with the vendor.

Used Microsoft dynamics AX2012R2 to instruct and provide all required setup to complete 2 warehouses inventory as well as 2 retail showrooms.

Job Responsibilities

Provided IT services whilst maintaining the complete IT system, troubleshooting, documenting, upgrading and repairing computer hardware, software and peripherals.

Analysed customer needs, defined solutions and recommended on IT equipment, software, services and training based on approved standards.

Analysed, defined, evaluated and implemented tools to improve the quality and effectiveness monitoring/ administration tasks and enhance security levels.

Responded to Customer Service/Helpdesk incident requests in a manner consistent with IT Service Level Guidelines. Provided analysis, problem definition and business solutions for the individual and their specific problems and requests.

Diagnosed and troubleshoot system problems and coordinated with other IT Specialists or external resources for resolution.

Received, set up, tested and installed new computer systems, hardware and software.

Defined and documented standard procedures for installation, maintenance and support of hardware and software. Assigned Security Roles on each department, in AX 2012 Software to control user's access to data through a set of access levels and permissions.

Managed Microsoft Dynamic AX to help organize, automate, and optimize processes; provided technical support to end users.

Arranged IT department strategies and future plans to ensure that the existing technology sustains and extends the company's strategies and helps achieve its strategic goals and objectives.

Aldouri Group as IT SUPERVISOR

Sep 2009 to Jan 2014

KEYACHIEVEMENTS:

Provided technical and troubleshooting assistance to over 12 branches, 2 warehouses and 2 factories (i.e., operating systems, hardware and software).

Set up and configured all system and technical requirements for opening a new store (P.O.S software installation and configuration, photo copier, network/internet system, telephone system/lines).

Implemented ERP system Project "Mcrosoft Dynamics RMS & Headquarter" with a Mcrosoft partner "A Futtaim Technology".

Contributed with the inventory of 10 retails branches and shared the accurate and detailed report with IT Manager. Attended and opened 4 new company branches arranged all IT installation store back server, POS machines, scales, CCTV & security, fingerprint.

Created ADD Server and Backup Copy of the whole company data clouding.

Provided Wintrade Software support and fixed all users issues.

Installed VoIP Grandstream telephones on all company branches with Spectrum IT solution Company.

Assigned security role on each department, for Microsoft dynamics RMS HQ.

Job Responsibilities:

Reported directly to the IT Manager with responsibility for leading and monitoring the daily jobs/duties of a highly skilled team of 4 Assistants (2 helpdesk support & 2 IT technicians).

Labelled all IT equipment as per the device type criteria and specific format; deployed all items into Microsoft dynamic RMS store.

Implemented all strategies for all IT operations, ensured compliance to all deadlines and provided upgrade to all systems as per requirement.

Analyzed all IT infrastructures and prepared reports to be submitted to senior management; performed research on all technological solutions and provide support to all procurement procedures.

Designed and executed IT policies and procedures to design all IT infrastructures and maintain compliance to all

standards and policies and administer efficient working of all IT equipment and hardware.

Collaborated with department personnel and designed innovative solutions for all IT issues and maintained all

Collaborated with department personnel and designed innovative solutions for all IT issues and maintained a hardware and software for processes according to security requirements.

 $\label{lem:continuous} \mbox{Developed and oversaw the installation of systems, which include software and hardware.}$

^ Back to Top

Education

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Win XP, Vista, Seven, Eight, Ten		
Server 2003,2008,2012,2016		
Mac OS		
MS Office: 2003,2007,2013,2016		
MS Dynamics: RMS & HQ, AX 2012Fp, 2012 R		
Microsoft Sql Server 2008,2012,2014,2016		
Kofax Express 3.2, RSSQL 5.05.001		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
ENGLISH				
ARABIC				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.